I got my wires crimped up ready to clip
in but it's obviously dark as [__] so
I'm going to come back tomorrow finish
up in the daylight catch me in a moment
C feeding the solar wires down bringing
through this cabinet that way we can
hide them a little
bit little tape on it like so keep it
from moving feed this on
down let's go get these things to the
roof make sure my wires are the right
length I'm not going to connect them
right now cuz it's live got to make sure
it's clean that's the most important
thing that right there is a problem that
wire hitting that I'm going to put
another piece of protector on there to
keep it from
rubbing okay I really want to keep it as
far as I can out of this Valley as you
can see water's been collecting here I
don't want it to be in a puddle so I'm
going to put it as far away as I can
about like
that put this in there to hold it so my
holes don't move on me when I'm
pre-drilling it
and ain't moving I always use mastic
tape not only does it seal but it also
sticks this mastic tape after it sits up
here in the hot sun for a few days you
won't even need the [__] screws
always put two layers on there when you
put it on you see it blow out from
underneath and you'll know there's no
way in hell that that [__] can Le I want
you to see when I screw this down I want
you to watch that mastic squirt out the
sign see how it's Caked Up see how it's
bulging out there ain't no water can get
in if you got ceiling squirting out
tighten these up I got to turn like this
cuz water flows over the roof like this
when you driving it'll run around the
boot it also protects water from coming
into these infield PS in the back that's
why we didn't connect it no shocky this
is a DC breaker 15
amp that in there just tighten these up
by hand just to make sure DC breaker in
check it before we cut it on make sure I
have everything wired correctly the
double insulated solar wire is different
than that other number 10 we've been
using in it
kid
negative now that I have my positive and
negative both landed I'm going to go
plug them in and I'm going to make sure
I have everything wired up correctly
using my voltmeter F solar slogan if it
clicks it
fits damn listen
H damn two in a row check our voltmeter
to check solar charge you put your red
to red wire black to black wire you
should get a positive value 46 Vols to
confirm I'm going to put my black to red
and my red to black I should get a
negative value once you've confirmed
your voltage is correct you can wire it
in and turn it on always confirm really
tighten now with a
screwdriver now the battery while I'm
hoping it'll reach I think it
will battery cable hooked up now we can
see if the system works
got the solar on panel showed up 43
volts of solar going in charging we have
confirmed it has input and output now I
feel safe putting everything else in
knowing that the battery system is going
to work just fine cut your solar off
unplug your battery everything
works back in all righty that is back
where it needs to go my battery cable
over the
sensors back on right here hot
down
boom charge
it charge my battery [__] yeah all we
have left to do is run our AC inputs and
outputs from here they have this drop
cord running out here for the input let
me show you needs to be a 30 amp service
at 125
volts that matches up with my 3500 WT
inverter in there what a [__]
coincidence this is going to come in
here
just
kid like 10 gauge wire I'm have to put
this one in a second because I need to
get that AC input in first this is the
old feed here take it a
loose this wire really Overkill it'll
never use this much
neutral that little symbol is your
ground L is your hot n is your neutral
that's all you need to know for 120 I
change this R connector neutral is in
ground is
in hot is
in breaker is in we are wired up last
one is this 120 charging same
thing we push it the button see if it go
[Music]
boom solar on there's my meter over here
turn this on
always check the very end of a circuit
if it's right there it'll be right
everywhere else in between we should be
getting 120 hey 120 volts bing bing bing
let's hit the button you here
humming
[Music]
[Applause]
hey hot Dam hot Dam it's twerking it's
twerking now I got to add my smart Chun
so we can have remote monitoring to
always check the battery level looks
like a good spot for it don't it
connected there's no voltage going to it
anywhere so we put it now you know why I
keep my [__] belt di in my battery
cables go ahead and grab it like
so hardest part is getting all them
little wires in
there go ahead and get it on the other
side see that coming off ain't coming
off in no way shape kind of form is it
man on
[Music]
there last little thing this has got to
clip into the positive terminal and then
plug in there that way it completes the
system so it can tell the voltage be a
[Music]
[__] ready in to the little hole
connected here it is got install an
update welcome to technology now we have
to set our battery parameters so the
shunt knows what the hell it's
controlling now we should get solar
in why is it not charging because the
shun thinks the battery is all the way
full we have to set the parameter so
it'll allow energy in update [__] to set
our battery parameters we come in here
Max charge voltage 29.6 all charge
voltage on this
29.6 I'm going to put it a little lower
than that I don't want it to get all the
way full I'm going to make our Max
voltage rate 29.2 you don't want it to
be all the way full like a bottle of
water that sunit might explode 230 amp
hours put our discharge floor at 15%
state of charge how are we going to set
our state of charge that is how full
this battery is let's pull up a chart
here I have a lithium battery charge
chart we see on a 24 volt 100% rest is
27.2 wow 100% charge
29.2 this lines up so if our voltage is
25.6 eight that would put us where oo
somewhere low we're down here in the 25%
range state of charge I'm going to put
25% our charge voltage is 29.2 our
charge voltage is going to go with
27.2 battery floor 230 amp hours
everything is set it's now allowing
solar into the battery as you can see
it's very cloudy out there not a whole
lot of sun but we're now putting energy
in instead of burning it off the shump
thought the battery was full so it
wasn't allowing any energy in there it's
a safety measure also a transmitter that
tells you exactly how much energy is
going out watch when I hit the
[Music]
button inverter is on pulling almost 4
amps inverter is off we have have solar
going in let's check a couple things to
make sure everything's working in here
fan cut
on light cut on cut our fridge onto
electric huh 280 WTS going out this
opgrade system is complete we have 120
output we have solar input we have 12vt
output everything is working confirmed
through smart monitoring in real time on
a phone this [__] has been Freedom
wagon it's not quite done he got a
little more finishing touches to do but
his [__] has a heartbeat Cletus
[Music]